Guide to the Cornell Migrant Program records, [ca. 1953-2005]
Cornell Migrant Program records, [ca. 1953-2005]
- Series V. Discrimination, Cultural Groups and Multi-Cultural Arts Project
  - Cost of being a Latino woman in New York State, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Women in the migrant agricultural labor force - Embrey, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Farmworker women speak out, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Women Latino migrant farmworkers settled in upstate New York - Biermayr-Jenzano, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Haitian programming (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Migrant Heritage Studies Kit: Haitian Component - Geneseo (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Rural Opportunities Inc. correspondence concerning Haitian services - Embrey, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Creole class, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Haitian Cornell Cooperative Extension newsletter article (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Haitian Farmworker: Understanding their culture, seminar, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Haiti reference materials (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Haitian entrants (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Wayne County Haitian Migrant Farmworkers Study - Yamashita, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Haitian night photos (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Demele: "Making It" - Rose Marie Chierici, folder 1: Dissertation University of Rochester, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Demele: "Making It" - Chierici, folder 2 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Demele: "Making It" - Chierici, folder 3 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Marion Village - Harassment of farmworkers, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Marion Village - Intercultural Awareness Committee (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Marion Village - Harassment of farmworkers, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Marion news article, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Marion's first Hispanic welcoming festival, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Marion and Cornell Cooperative Extension, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Cornell Cooperative Extension Social Trends Conference On Racism, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Cornell Cooperative Extension Social Trends Conference - Hiring workshop, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - White supremacist groups in Onondaga County, 1990-1995 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Oswego County attack on workers, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - A Survey of migrant farmworkers in Wayne County New York, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Don Barr's Cornell undergrad course, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Don Barr's papers (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Wayne County minority performing arts grants and budget, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - WCMAP services, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Wayne County Minority Performing Arts Events, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Minority Arts Series, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Wayne County Minority Performing Arts final report, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Wayne County Minority Performing Arts miscellany, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Wayne County Minority Performing Arts, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Wayne County Minority Performing Arts, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Wayne County Minority Performing Arts overview (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Mexican Fiesta (Box 5, Folder 43)
- Series VI. Health
  - Study of Wells by CATA, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - IMETF - Migrant health, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Problems in management of migrant health programs - GA0, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Cross cultural counseling - USDA, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - National Advisory Council on migrant health, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - New York State statewide strategies for health care for migrant farmworkers report, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Aids and migrant farmworkers (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - HIV and migrants, 1992-1997 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - East coast entitlement project (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Migrant health articles, 1979, 1990, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Oak Orchard Health Economic Impact Study, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - GIs among migrant farmworkers in New York State, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Health care campaign testimony - Engman, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Health and field sanitation, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - National Migrant Health Resource Center (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - 6-16 farmworker health care availability and utilization - Rural Opportunities Inc., 1987 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Maternal and child health services among farmworkers in Niagara County, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Effects of cultural and structural factors - Hales, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Migrant health centers - health education workshop, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Lockport migrant health and dental clinics, 1996-2001 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Chautauqua health feasibility, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Orange - Ulster Clinic Warwick, 1980-1983 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Rushville Clinic, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Finger Lakes migrant health coordination project, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Rural Health and Safety Council, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Hudson Valley migrant health, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Mobile health unit (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Transportation (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Health education proposal- Lockport, 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Suffolk County migrant health project, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Orange County migrant health education, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Migrant health education project, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Migrant/rural health, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Medicaid and migrants, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - EFNEP guidelines (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - EFNEP, 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Pick and choose video (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - EFNEP, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Cornell - Florida EFNEP (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Assessment of migrant EFNEP, Wayne County, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - EFNEP proposal Wayne County, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Migrant family communication project - Health related audio tapes, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Migrant family communication project scripts (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Migrant family communication project scripts 2 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Farmworkers eating contaminated fish (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Alcohol use among migrant laborers - Kunitz-Morales, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Migrant health articles, 1978-1985 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Chi - Wayne County field work - Correspondence and notes, 1983-1985 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Sampling Produce for Surveying Health Conditions of Migrant Farmworkers - Chi, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Health Care and Health States of Migrant Farmworkers in Wayne County - Chi, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Health Care and Health Status of Migrant Farmworkers in New York State (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Medical Utilization Patterns of Migrant Farmworkers in Wayne County New York - Chi, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Variation in Subjective Well Being Among Migrant Farmworkers in New York - Chi, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Health Effects of Agricultural Production, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Employment and Economic Profiles of Black Migrant Farmworkers in New York - Chi, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Research on Migratory Farmworkers - Chi and White-Means, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Index of General Well Being as a Measure (of Migrant Farmworkers) - Chi (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Health Needs, Economic Impacts and Self Help for Migrant Farmworkers - Proposal, Chi (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - New York Migrant Health Status Survey Instrument - Chi, 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Knowledge and Utilization of Subsidized Health Care in Rural New York - White-Means, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Health Status and Economic Productivity of Migrant Farmworkers in Orange County, New York - Interim report, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Drinking, Farm and Camp Life - Chi and McClain, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Migrant Farmworkers Productivity - White-Means proposal, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Chi Study in Orange and Ulster Counties - Correspondence and notes, 1985-1987 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Hired Farmworkers: Health and Well Being at Risk - GAO, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Farmworker Outreach Manual - East Coast Migrant Health Project (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - East Coast Stream Forum, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Migrant Health Centers Referral Directory, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Proceedings of Migrant Farmworker Stream Forum, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Bilingual patient education materials, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Farmworker enumeration project, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 71)
- Series VII. Pesticides and Occupational Health
  - Farm safety review, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - EPA Spanish booklet, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Occupational Health and Safety (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Safety sheets - New York Farm Bureau, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Occupation health of migrant farmworkers in the United States, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Pesticide education project, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Pesticide use and misuse: Farmworkers speak, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Pesticides and farmworkers AFDP, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Pesticides residue hazards to farmworkers -NIOSH, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Pesticides publications - California, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Potential Pesticides Exposure of Migrant Farmworkers - Morse and Mclellan, Pesticides education packets, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Employee training - Pesticide safety: Embrey (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Right to Know kits, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Right to Know Law - Resources and correspondence, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Rural Opportunities Inc. MOST project, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Pesticides safety for farmworkers- EPA, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Occupational health of migrant farmworkers in U.S. - FJF: Wilk, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - EPA trainer's workshop packets, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Farm medic (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - OSH - California resources (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Farm guide to the Right to Know Law-Cornell, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - DSHA hazardous communication standard, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Teaching Pesticide Safety and Health Workshop by Larson, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Clothing for Pesticide Users - Cornell, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Protective Clothing - Coffman (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Pesticide info (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Work group on pesticide safety and health - A. Larson, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - NIOSH proposal - Engman and Chi, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - EPA materials, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - EPA worker protection standards, 1993-1996 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - RCAP/MESA - Virginia, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Pesticide handbook - Farmworker Legal Services of New York (FLSNY), 1994 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - New York Center for Agricultural Medicine and Health (NYCAMH) - Bassett Hospital (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Pesticides on farms - Government Accountability Office (GAO), 1993 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Ergonomics for farmworkers - National Institute of Occupational Safety and Health (NIOSH), 2001 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Vocational rehab proposal - Cornell, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Workers Information (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Attorney general and pesticides settlement, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Farmworkers and pesticides - Environmental advocate, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Farmworkers OSH project - Embrey, 1998-1901 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - 41 Rural Opportunities Inc. vocational rehab project, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Farmworker women and breast cancer, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Fields of Poison - California, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Agriculture safety and health - News line, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - News articles - Migrant farmworkers and OSH MESA Environmental Health Resource Manual, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - California ag ergonomics research program, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Workers Compensation (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Workers Compensation Increasing Farmworker's Access - FJF, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - University of Rochester environmental justice grant, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 49)
- Series VIII. Services
  - Art exhibits - Geneseo (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Eastern farmworkers in Wayne County, 1980-1999 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - PASS national reports, 1998-2000 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - BOCES Geneseo migrant center publications (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Brockport migrant education program, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Brockport Ecumenical Outreach Committee, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Orange County - The Alamo, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Report: activities for migrant workers in Wyoming County, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - New York State agricultural child care (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Migrant child care (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Finger Lakes Office of Social Ministry (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Ontario County migrant program meetings, 1984-1992 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Rural Employment Services - Department of Labor, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Services for farm and farmworker families in transition - New York State (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Food stamps, 1993-1997 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Legal services (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Wayne Finger Lakes tutorial, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Black Focus newsletter, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Women, Options and Work - Geneseo newsletter, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Real Talk - Geneseo newsletter, 1984-1988 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Geneseo scholarship (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Wayne County Rural Ministry, 1981-1985 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Outreach training - Wayne County, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Directory of Wayne County agencies, 1980-1989 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Services - Wayne County - Embrey, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Services for migrant farmworkers in Wayne County, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Services for migrant farmworkers in Wayne - English and Spanish, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Services for migrant farmworkers in Wayne - English and Spanish, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Services for migrant farmworkers in Wayne - English and Spanish, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Services for migrant farmworkers in Wayne - English and Spanish, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Services for migrant farmworkers in Wayne - English and Spanish, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Services for migrant farmworkers in Wayne - English and Spanish, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Services for migrant farmworkers in Wayne - English and Spanish, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Services for migrant farmworkers in Wayne - Eng and Span, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Services for migrant farmworkers in Wayne - English and Spanish, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Services for migrant farmworkers in Wayne - English and Spanish, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Services for migrant farmworkers in Wayne - English and Spanish, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Services for migrant farmworkers in Wayne - English and Spanish, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Agency services to farmworkers - New York State ICC, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - NAFO members, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Mexican migrant farmworkers - Perception of services in Wayne County - Zelaya, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Funding profile of farmworker services, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Harvester training - Mitchell, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Project Reach, Steuben County, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Program Funding, Inc., 1973-1975 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Economic independence- K. Tobin, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Tobin - Mattera correspondence, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - FFI - Slide show, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Rural New York Reporter - RNYFO, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Committee for Farmwork Justice (Rural Opportunities Inc.), 1980-1989 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Making Laws Work for Women - Noble Hanson (Tobin), 1977 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Dignity for Farmworkers - Full Employment - Noble Hanson (Tobin), 1977 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - S. Mitchell correspondence, 1979, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Agriculture Careers Exploration Program - RNYFO (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - RNYFO board materials, 1979-1982 (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Rural Housing Action Corp. Inc. (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Significant Issues Effecting Migrant Farmworkers in the 80's - Mitchell, Rural Opportunities Inc. (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Farmwork and Farmworkers in New York State - S. Mitchell, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Willie's Valley, Williamson - Rural Opportunities Inc. report, 1980-1989 (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - RNYFO empowerment proposal, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Vigilant newsletter RNYFO, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - The Farmworker - Rural Opportunities Inc. newsletter, 1992, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Voices - Rural Opportunities Inc. newsletter, 1994, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - Rural Opportunities Inc. Building Blocks newsletter, 1996, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Program Funding Inc. annual report, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Program Funding Inc. annual report, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - RNYFO annual report, 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - RNYFO annual report, 1978-1979 (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - RNYFO annual report, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - RNYFO annual report, 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - RNYFO annual report, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - RNYFO annual report, 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - RNYFO board materials, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 73)
  - Rural Opportunities Inc. annual report, 1984-1985 (Box 8, Folder 74)
  - Rural Opportunities Inc. annual conference, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 75)
  - Pennsylvania Farmworker Opportunities, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 76)
  - Rural Opportunities Inc. annual report, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - Rural Opportunities Inc. annual report, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - Rural Opportunities Inc. directory and services, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - Rural Opportunities Inc. annual report, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - Rural Opportunities Inc. annual report, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - Rural Opportunities Inc. annual report, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - Rural Opportunities Inc. yearbook, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 83)
  - Rural Opportunities Inc. annual report, 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 84)
  - Rural Opportunities Inc. annual report, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 85)
  - Rural Opportunities Inc. Profiles of Success, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 86)
  - Rural Opportunities Inc. Farmworker Hall of Fame - Engman induction, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - Rural Opportunities Inc. Farmworker Hall of Fame, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 88)
  - Rural Opportunities Inc. Farmworker Hall of Fame - Embrey induction, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 89)
- Series IX. Education and Children
  - Migrant child census New York, 1977-1996 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Migrant children with limited English in New York State, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Educating migrant children New York, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Bureau Migrant Education - Correspondence, grants, flyers, 1974-1978 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Health care and Education: Guide For Migrant School Nurse, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Work Experience and Career Education for Migrant Children ERIC, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Guidelines for Daycare Program for Migrant Infants and Toddlers, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Guidebook: In Camp Education for Migrant Farmworkers - Geneseo, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Migrant child welfare conference - Embrey-Wood, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Migrant child welfare - Review of literature and legislation, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Migrant child welfare - Executive summary, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - National Migrant Foundation, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - New York State migrant education historical brief - Gaige (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Farmworker youth report, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Isolation of Migrant Teens - Embrey (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Child labor: Characteristics of working children - GAO, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Child labor in agriculture - GAO, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Child labor on farms general information (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Consortium call newsletters, 1980-1984 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Parents as trainers - New York State migrant education, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Migrant attrition project - Oneonta, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Child abuse and neglect prevention proposal, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Child Maltreatment Among United States East Coast Migrant Farmworkers - Larson. Doris. Alvarez, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Child abuse and neglect workshop, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Children of Migrant Farmworkers at High Risk for Maltreatment New York State - Alvarez. Doris. Larson, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Directory of Migrant Education Programs in Eastern Stream States, 1989-1990 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - ERIC publications on migrant children's education and health, 1990-1994 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Directory of Florida contacts, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Migrant farmworker students - Decisions involved in post-secondary participation, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - R. Bove Memorial Migrant Students Poets and Writers Festival, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - First New York State tutorial conference, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Consortium bylaws (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Consortium five year plan, 1987-1991 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Parental involvement - migrant students (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Literacy VISTA sites (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Migrant education AIDS programs (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - ESCORT (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Effects of Mobility on Learning - Wolverton, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - New York State MEDP state training, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - New York State migrant tutorials consortium, 1977-1980 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Tutorial publications (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Tutorial Health Coordination - Norton, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Cornell exploration of tutorial, 1976-1977 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Early Childhood Center proposal, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Task force meeting with State Education Dept. civil rights, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Minority staff concerns committee, 1987-1992 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Parent involvement in hiring, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Racial and ethnic distribution of public school students and staff New York State, 1989-1990 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - New York State Education Department Appreciation of Cultural Diversity Conference, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Multicultural education task force correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Migrant education legislative issues (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Migrant Education Parent Advisory Council (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Consortium formation of multicultural task force, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Migrant education workshop on racism, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Multicultural task force goal setting (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Racism task force survey, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Racism task force recommendations, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Racism task force report, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Recruitment, hiring and retention of minority staff - METF, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Diversity in-service for Wayne tutorial staff - Fox, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Multicultural education task force meeting minutes, 1988-1991 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Migrant report - Reilinger, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Migrant Education in New York State: An Assessment - Rellinger, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Migrant Farmworker - Youth and Adults At Risk - Castania, Engman, Embrey, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 64)
- Series X. Labor Management Programs
  - Agent newsletter articles, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Agriculture newsletters with Embrey articles, 1980-1989 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Labor news articles - Embrey (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - News service articles, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Articles for agent newsletters, 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Women In agri-business, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Farm labor laws panel, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Holt meetings, 1982, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Farm labor management with Holt at Tompkins County Community College, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Farm labor laws panel, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Apple picking - Embrey, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Worker preparation presentation - Fruit schools, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - MSAWPA enactment, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Ag impact, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Farmworker laws panel, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - New York State minimum wage increase, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Right To Know Law, 1983-1985 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Employee orientation outline, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 18)